Andrés Bonilla

Brooklyn, New York, United States



linkedin.com/in/andresbonilla



andresbonilla@gmail.com

Summary

Computer engineer with 10+ years of experience as a web developer and solution architect. Used to fast-paced agency environments and demanding technical requirements. Big believer in test/behavior-driven development. Favorite tools include Node.js, React, MongoDB, Cucumber, Heroku and Spark AR.

Experience



Full Stack Engineer

Raincoat

May 2020 - Present (2 months +)

Mostly front end development of React app for purchasing hurricane insurance with automatic payout based on real-time NOAA weather data APIs. React, Sass, Stripe integration with automated UI testing using Cucumber with Puppeteer.

Solution Architect

BBH New York

Mar 2016 - May 2020 (4 years 3 months)

Development and oversight of mostly web-based tech work. Projects include E-Commerce projects using Magento and Shopify, Brand site development using WordPress and Drupal, Augmented Reality projects using Spark AR and 8th wall, experiential web projects and rapid prototyping for pitches. Led a team of 7 developers on a large corporate brand site ecosystem build of 12 uniquely styled, ADA compliant, fully responsive sites for Marriott. Developed an in-house UX diagramming tool for the strategy department consisting of a React frontend and an Express API. All projects typically heavy on animation and interaction with full responsiveness.

Senior Interactive Developer

Domani Studios

Mar 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Design and implementation of front and back end code for commercial clients. Responsive user experiences with clean, DRY, maintainable code. More project ownership than before, meaning handling the tech side of entire projects on my own rather than splitting the job with another developer.

Interactive Developer

Domani Studios

Nov 2012 - Mar 2015 (2 years 5 months)

Full stack web development for commercial clients. Front end heavy projects with complex animations and interactivity. Responsive user interface development with clean, DRY, maintainable code.



Freelance Web Application Developer

Self Employed

Jun 2009 - Jun 2014 (5 years 1 month)

Ruby on Rails web application development and native iOS application development with Objective-C. Clients include WapaTV, Autoridad de Acueductos y Alcantarillados de Puerto Rico, MCS, Snickers, Colegio Bautista de Caguas, and Out of the Box. Most projects are deployed on Heroku.

altruik Front End Developer

Altruik

Oct 2010 - Nov 2012 (2 years 2 months)

Ruby on Rails and javascript user interface development for an automated SEO platform. Responsive frontend development heavy on data visualization.

Web Developer

Websoft of Puerto Rico

Jan 2010 - Oct 2010 (10 months)

Web application development using .net MVC and jQuery.

■ Student Researcher

NOAA-CREST

Aug 2006 - Aug 2008 (2 years 1 month)

NOAA student researcher. Assisted with construction and calibration of the the UPRM LIDAR laboratory. Advisor: Hamed Parsiani.

Research Assistant

University of California, Berkeley

Jun 2008 - Jul 2008 (2 months)

EECS Research Assistant at University of California, Berkeley.

Action-inference modeling using combined Petri-Bayes Nets in Java.

Advisor: Jerome Feldman

Education

■ University of Puerto Rico at Mayaguez

BS, Computer Engineering

2004 - 2009

Magna Cum Laude

Honors & Awards

Site of the Day for Westin Finds from Afar - Awwwards

Nov 2013

Site of the Day award on November 4, 2013 for the Westin Finds from Afar site.

Site of the Day for Love FILA - Awwwards

Jul 2016

Site of the Day award for Love FILA site, a FILA collaboration with designer Marion Bartoli.

Skills

JavaScript • Web Development • Behavior-Driven Development (BDD) • Front-end • User Interface • Mobile Applications • React.js • Node.js • HTML • CSS